A Guide to Council and Committee Records of the Virginia Information Technologies Agency, 2009-2018
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Council and Committee Records of the Virginia Information Technologies Agency, 2009-2018
The Library of Virginia
53611
1 cu. ft. (1 box)
Virginia Information Technologies Agency
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Accession 53614 transferred by the Virginia Information Technologies Agency, 5 May 2022.
Biographical/Historical Information
The Virginia Information Technologies Agency (VITA) was approved by the General Assembly on 2 April 2003 during Governor Mark R. Warner's administration to provide information technology that enables the government to better serve the public. VITA serves as the Commonwealth's consolidated, centralized information technology organization. The newly created agency superseded the Department of Information Technology and the Department of Technology Planning. Its responsibilities include the operation of information technology infrastructure for the executive branch agencies, the governance of information technology investments, and the procurement of technology on behalf of other state agencies and institutions of higher learning. The Information Technology Investment Board (ITIB) was created along with VITA to review and prioritize enterprise-wide technology investments across state government. The Board is also responsible for appointing the Chief Information Officer (CIO) to serve as VITA's chief administrative officer.
Responsibility for the 911 Services Board and the Virginia Geographic Information Network Advisory Board was transferred from VITA to the Virginia Dept. of Emergency Services in 2020 (HB 1003, Chap. 423, approved March 23, 2020).
Chief Information Officers include: Lemuel C. Stewart, Jr., 2003-2009; Samuel Nixon, Jr., 2010-2015; Nelson P. Moe, 2015-2020.
Scope and Content
Council and Committee Records, 2009-2018, consist of 1 box and are arranged in original order. These records document the administration of the VITA contract with Northrop Grumman. Includes Corrective Action Plans, 2009; Correspondence, 2007-2019; Independent Accountants' Reports, 2007-2017; Reports of Controls Placed in Operation and Tests of Operating Effectiveness, 2006-2017; Confidential Security Audits (RESTRICTED), 2007-2010; Comprehensive Infrastructure Agreement, 2005-2006; and various other reports and plans related to the transition and deliverables.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the original order.
Contents List
- Identity Management Standards Advisory Council (IMSAC), 2015-2018.
  - Meeting, 2015 Dec 7. (Box 1)
  - Meeting, 2016 Mar 7. (Box 1)
  - Meeting, 2016 May 2. (Box 1)
  - Meeting, 2016 June 30. (Box 1)
  - Dedicated meeting for public comment, 2016 June 30. (Box 1)
  - Information Technology Resource Management (ITRM) Guidance Document - Authenticators and Lifecycle Management (draft), 2016 July 20. (Box 1)
  - Information Technology Resource Management (ITRM) Guidance Document - Electronic Authentication (draft), 2016 July 20. (Box 1)
  - Meeting, 2016 Sept 12. (Box 1)
  - Dedicated meeting for public comment, 2016 Sept 12. (Box 1)
  - Information Technology Resource Management (ITRM) Guidance Document - Identity Proofing and Verification (draft), 2016 Sept 12. (Box 1)
  - Information Technology Resource Management (ITRM) Guidance Document - Identity Trust Frameworks (draft), 2016 Sept 12. (Box 1)
  - IMSAC Guidance Document - Identity Trust Frameworks (draft), 2016 Sept 30. (Box 1)
  - IMSAC Guidance Document - Identity Proofing and Verification (draft), 2016 Sept 30. (Box 1)
  - IMSAC Guidance Document - Digital Identity Assertions (draft), 2016 Oct 12. (Box 1)
  - IMSAC Guidance Document - Federation and Participant Requirements (draft), 2016 Oct 12. (Box 1)
  - Meeting (no agenda or minutes), 2016 Dec 5. (Box 1)
  - Dedicated meeting for public comment, 2016 Dec 5. (Box 1)
  - IMSAC Guidance Document - Authenticators and Lifecycle Management (draft), 2016 Dec 5. (Box 1)
  - IMSAC Guidance Document - Electronic Authentication (draft), 2016 Dec 5. (Box 1)
  - IMSAC Guidance Document - Identity Management of Non-Person Entities (draft), 2017 Jan 4. (Box 1)
  - Meeting, 2017 June 5. (Box 1)
  - Dedicated meeting for public comment, 2017 June 5. (Box 1)
  - Meeting, 2017 Oct 24. (Box 1)
  - Dedicated meeting for public comment, 2017 Oct 24. (Box 1)
  - IMSAC Guidance Document - Privacy, Security and Confidentiality of Identity Information (draft), 2017 Oct 24. (Box 1)
  - Meeting, 2018 May 24. (Box 1)
  - Meeting, 2018 July 16. (Box 1)
- Information Technology Advisory Council (ITAC), 2014-2017.
  - Meeting, 2015 Feb 27. (Box 1)
  - Meeting, 2015 May 4. (Box 1)
  - Meeting, 2015 Aug 3. (Box 1)
  - Meeting, 2015 Oct 26. (Box 1)
  - Meeting, 2016 Mar 14. (Box 1)
  - Meeting, 2016 May 2. (Box 1)
  - Meeting, 2016 Aug 1. (Box 1)
  - Meeting, 2016 Oct 31. (Box 1)
  - Meeting, 2017 Mar 13. (Box 1)
  - Meeting, 2017 June 12. (Box 1)
  - Meeting, 2017 Dec 11. (Box 1)
- Health Information Technology Standards Advisory Committee (HITSAC), 2009-2016.
  - Charter, 2009 Aug 20. (Box 1)
  - Meeting, 2009 July 16. (Box 1)
  - Meeting, 2009 July 30. (Box 1)
  - Meeting, 2009 Aug 20. (Box 1)
  - Meeting - Committee members and committee liaisons, 2009 Sept 4. (Box 1)
  - Meeting, 2009 Sept 17. (Box 1)
  - Meeting, 2009 Sept 29. (Box 1)
  - Meeting, 2009 Oct 15. (Box 1)
  - Meeting, 2009 Oct 22. (Box 1)
  - Meeting, 2009 Nov 19. (Box 1)
  - Meeting - Initial Standards Briefing Presentations, 2010 Jan 21. (Box 1)
  - Meeting, 2010 Feb 18. (Box 1)
  - Meeting, 2011 Jan 20. (Box 1)
  - Meeting, 2011 Feb 17. (Box 1)
  - Meeting, 2011 Mar 17. (Box 1)
  - Meeting, 2011 Apr 21. (Box 1)
  - Meeting, 2011 May 19. (Box 1)
  - Meeting, 2011 June 16. (Box 1)
  - Meeting, 2011 Aug 18. (Box 1)
  - Meeting, 2011 Oct 20. (Box 1)
  - Meeting, 2011 Dec 15. (Box 1)